Guide to the Rice University Will Rice College Records, 1957-2017 UA 073
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Will Rice College Records
1957-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Will Rice College (Rice University).
UA 073
19 Linear Feet (39 boxes + oversize materials)
0.0037 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_001 (0.0037 GB)
0.0019 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_002 (0.0019 GB)
0.014 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_003 (0.014 GB)
0.019 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_004 (0.019 GB)
0.016 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_005 (0.016 GB)
0.00018 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_006 (0.00018 GB)
0.003 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_007 (0.003 GB)
165 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_008 (0.165 GB)
0.06 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_009 (0.06 MB)
0.163 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_009 (0.163 GB)
0.122 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_010 (0.122 GB)
0.122 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_011 (0.122 GB)
0.005 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_012 (0.005 GB)
0.071 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_013 (0.071 GB)
1.25 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0073aip_014 (1.25 GB)
Documents, publications, minutes, including constitution and by-laws, as well as correspondence files, news clippings and theatrical information and social activities created and maintained by residents of Will Rice College. Will Rice was opened in 1912 and became one of the men's colleges in 1957. It went co-ed in 1977.
Historical Sketch
Will Rice College is named for William M. Rice, Jr., the nephew and namesake of the founder, a Houston businessman, and trustee of the Institute from 1899 until his death in 1944. Rice was the chairman of the board of trustees from 1941 until 1944. Will Rice College includes South Hall, the first dormitory built at Rice. It was part of Residential Group Number One until this was partitioned when the residential college system was adopted.
Will Rice was opened in 1912 and became one of the men's colleges in 1957. It went co-ed in 1977.
Scope and Contents
It is an extensive collection of college documents, publications, minutes, including constitution and by-laws, as well as correspondence files, news clippings and theatrical information and social activities created and maintained by residents of Will Rice College. Dates range from 1957-2013.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The source and date of the original material is unknown. The 1957-61 material was received May 3, 1996. November 1, 2000, 8 large record storage boxes were received from CeCe King, College Coordinator. Additional materials dating from 1958-1968 were acquired in January 2005. Joyce Courtois, College Coordinator, donated materials over the summer of 2013.
Related Material
See Rice University Archives for records of other Rice University residential colleges. Contact Woodson Research Center staff for assistance.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
awards; calendars; minutes (administrative records); photographs; clippings (information artifacts); constitutions; guidebooks; legal documents
Subjects (Corporations)
Will Rice College (Rice University).; Rice University--residential college system.
- Series I: Chronological Files, 1957-1996, 229116
  - Subseries A: 1957- 1960, 229321
    - Constitution, by-laws, 1957, 229332 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Administrative details-college residents, 1957-58, 229331 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Inter-college Council minutes, 1957-59, 229330 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Residents' lists, 1957-62, 229329 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Residents/housing, 1957-58, 1959-60, 229328 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Internal affairs, 1958-59, 229327 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Masters and external affairs, 1958-59, 229326 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Members' correspondence, 1958-59, 229325 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Entertainment budget accounts, 1958-59, 1960-61, 229324 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General college affairs, 1959-60, 229323 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1959-60, 229322 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: 1960-1961, 229308
    - Commons, 1960-61, 229319 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - College recommendations, 1960-61, 229320 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - External affairs, 1960-61, 229318 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Masters' affairs, 1960-61, 229317 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Masters' meetings, 1960-61, 229316 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Residential details, 1960-61, 229315 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Scholarship, 1960-61, 229314 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Students' correspondence, 1960-61, 229313 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Devolopment, 1961-62, 229312 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Diet Meetings, 1961-62, 229311 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Freshman week, 1961-62, 229310 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Students correspondence, 1961-62, 229309 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Subseries C: 1962-1963, 229291
    - Correspondence, 1962-63, 229307 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Entertainment budget accounts, 1962-1965, 229306 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Freshman week, 1962-63, 229305 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Masters's affairs, 1962-63, 1967-68, 229304 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Resident's list, 1962-63, 1963-64, 1964-65, 229303 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Withdrawals from Rice and commentaries, 1962-63, 229302 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Activities, 1963, 1970s, 229301 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Subseries D: 1963-1964, 229300 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_52f2f44ce92a133ae2145c127c810c4d)
    - Basement project, 1963-64, 229299 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - College building, 1963-64, 229298 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - College minutes, 1963-64, 229297 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Freshman week, 1963-64, 229296 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Members' correspondence, 1963-65, 229295 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Student council minutes, 1963-64, 229294 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - College lists, 1963-64, 229293 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Reports, 1964, 229292 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries E: 1964-1965, 229284
    - Correspondence, general, 1964-65, 229290 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Dean notes, 1964-65, 229289 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - General policy and rules, intercollege affairs, 1964-65, 229288 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Student Senate, 1964-65, 229287 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Relations with Dean of students, 1964-65, 229286 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Repairs, 1964-65, 229285 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subseries F: 1965-1966, 229278
    - Memoranda and lists, 1965-66, 229283 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Resident's list, 1965-66, 229282 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Subseries G: 1966-1967, 229281 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_a8b51aa2158780fdfe6dd62f08e637d6)
    - Discipline, 1966-67, 229280 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Freshman week, 1966, 229279 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Subseries H: 1967-1968, 229260
    - Freshman week, 1967-68, 229277 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Memoranda and minutes, 1967, 229276 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Resident lists, 1967, 229275 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Resident lists, 1967-68, 1968-69, 229274 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Subseries I: 1968-1969, 229273 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_625765e6ab0248e5d136c5fffcefdab2)
    - Academics, 1968-69, 229272 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Associates, 1968-69, 229271 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Committees, 1968-69, 229270 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Constitution, by-laws, rules, 1968-69, 229269 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Courses, 1968-69, 229268 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Elections, 1968-69, 229267 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fellows, 1968-69, 229266 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Financial, 1968-69, 1961-62, 229265 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - General business, 1968-69, 229264 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Maintenance 1968-69, 229263 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - President's file-Tom Plant, 1968-69, 229262 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Rosters, 1968-69, 229261 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Subseries J: 1969-1970, 229242
    - Alumni affairs, 1969-70, 229259 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Associates, 1969-70, 229258 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Committees, 1969-70, 229257 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Constitution, by-laws, rules, 1969-70, 229256 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Courses, 1969-70, 229255 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Court, 1969-70, 229254 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Damages, buildings and grounds, 1969-1970, 229253 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Fellows, 1969-70, 229252 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Financial, 1969-70, 229251 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Freshman week, 1969-70, 229250 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - General business, 1969-70, 229249 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Maintenance, 1969-70, 229248 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - President's file-Buford Alexander, 1969-70, 229247 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rosters, 1969-70, 229246 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - S.A.Business, 1969-70, 229245 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Social, 1969-70, 229244 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Speakers, 1969-70, 229243 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subseries J: 1970 - 1971, 229229
    - Academic possibilities, 1970-71, 229241 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Associates, 1970-71, 229240 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Committees, 1970-71, 229239 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Courses, 1970-71, 229238 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Elections, 1970-71, 229237 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Fellows, 1970-71, 229236 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Financial, 1970-71, 229235 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Freshman week, 1970-71, 229234 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - General business, 1970-71, 229233 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Off-campus, 229232 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - President's file-Dan King, 1970-71, 229231 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Rosters, 1970-71, 229230 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Subseries K: 1971-1972, 229222
    - Associates, 1971-72, 229228 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Committees, 1971-72, 229227 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Constitution, 1971-72, 229226 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Courses, 1971-72, 229225 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Elections, 1971-72, 229224 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Financial, 1971-72, 229223 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Subseries L: 1971-1972, 229217
    - Freshman week, 1971-72, 229221 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - General business, 1971-72, 229220 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - President's file-Bill Starnes, 1971-72, 229219 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Rosters, 1971-72, 229218 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Subseries M: 1972-1973, 229207
    - Associates, 1972-73, 229216 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Courses, 1972-73, 229215 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Elections, 1972-73, 229214 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Fellows, 1972-73, 229213 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Financial, 1972-73, 229212 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Freshman week, 1972-73, 229211 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - General business, 1972-73, 229210 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - President's file-Chuck Allen, 1972-73, 229209 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Rosters, 1972-73, 229208 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Subseries N: 1973-1974, 229193
    - Associates, 1973-74, 229206 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Committees, 1973-74, 229205 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1973-74, 229204 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Courses, 1973-74, 229203 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Elections, 1973-74, 229202 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Fellows, 1973-74, 229201 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Financial, 1973-74, 229200 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Freshman week, 1973, 229199 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - General business, 1973-74, 229198 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - President's file-Larry Gross, 1973-74, 229197 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Rosters, 1973-74, 229196 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Constitution, by-laws, 1973-79, 229195 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Masters and presidents meetings, 1974, 229194 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Subseries O: 1974-1975, 229181
    - Awards, 1974, 1980s, 229192 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Associates, 1974-75, 229191 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Constitution, by-laws, 1974-75, 229190 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Courses, 1974-75, 229189 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Elections, 1974-75, 229188 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Fellows, 1974-75, 229187 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Financial, 1974-75, 229186 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Freshman week, 1974-75, 229185 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - President's file-Scott Davis, 1974-75, 229184 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Rosters, 1974-75, 229183 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Associates, 1975-76, 229182 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Subseries P: 1975-1976, 229172
    - Committees, 1975-76, 229180 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Elections, 1975-76, 229179 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Fellows, 1975-76, 229178 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Financial, 1975-76, 229177 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Freshman week, 1975-76, 229176 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Masters and presidents meetings, 1975-76, 229175 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - President's file-John Dragovits, 1975-76, 229174 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Rosters, 1975-76, 229173 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Subseries Q: 1976-1996, 229117
    - Associates, 1976-77, 229171 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Committees, 1976-77, 229170 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Courses, 1976-77, 229169 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Elections, 1976-77, 229168 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Fellows, 1976-77, 229167 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Financial, 1976-77, 229166 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Freshman week, 1976, 229165 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - President's file, 1976-77, 229164 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Rosters, 1976-77, 229163 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Internal Affairs Committee, 1977-83, 229162 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Financial, 1977-87, 229161 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Rosters, 1978-91, 229160 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Commencement, 1979-96, 229159 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Protest, 1980, 229158 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Theatrical, 1980s-, 229157 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Constitution, by-laws, 1980-84, 229156 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Associates, 1982-84, 229155 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Associates, 1984-85, 229154 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Rosters, 1984-85, 229153 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Management Advisory Committee, 1984-86, 229152 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Associates, 1985-86, 229151 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - President's file-Bill Tucker, 1985-86, 229150 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rosters, 1985-86, 229149 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Associates, 1986-87, 229148 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fellows, 1986-90, 229147 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Rosters, 1986-87, 229146 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Masters, 1987, 229145 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Associates, 1987-88, 229144 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Committees, 1987-88, 229143 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Rosters, 1987-88, 229142 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Beer-Bike, 1987-90, 229141 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Will Rice Day, 1988, 229140 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Associates, 1988-89, 229139 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Rosters, 1988-89, 229138 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Financial, 1988-90, 229137 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1989, 229136 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Money Market accounts, 1988-90, 229135 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Piano fund, 1989, 229134 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Residential improvements, 1989-91, 229133 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Masters and Presidents meetings, 1990-94, 229132 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Awards, 1990-98, 229131 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Activities, 1990-91, 229130 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Minutes and notes, 1990-91, 229129 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Projects, 1990-91, 229128 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Room Jacks, Policies and rules, 1990, 229127 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Rosters, 1992-98, 229126 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Constitutions, by-laws, 1993, 229125 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Road Rally, 1993, 229124 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Committees, 1993-94, 229123 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Financial, 1993-94, 229122 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - President's file, 1993-94, 229121 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Rosters, 1993-94, 229120 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Committees, 1996, 229119 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - News clippings, 229118 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Series II: Publications, 1965-1996, 229101
  - Scatter Shot, 1965-66, 229115 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Will Rice College Profile, 1965-68, 229114 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - College Directions: What Next?, 1967, 229113 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Will Rice Whatever, Sept. 11, 1969, 229112 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The Will Rice Something*Or*Else, Sept. 23, 1969, 229111 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Individualist, Oct. 14, 1969, 229110 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Will Rice Guide to Houston 1977-78, 229109 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Additions and Alterations to Will Rice Commons, 1979, 229108 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - The Will Rice Phoenix, 1969-70, 229107 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - The Will Rice Phoenix, 1971-80, 229106 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - The Will Rice Phoenix, 1983-94, 1995-96, 229105 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - The Hook Report: A College in Jeopardy, n.d., 229104 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Handbook, [notes, proofs] 1974-75, 229103 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Handbook, [notes, proofs] 1977-78, 229102 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Series III: Diet Minutes, 1958-2000, 229080
  - 1958-59, 229100 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1960-62, 229099 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1962-63, 229098 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1960-64, 1965, 229097 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1964-65, 229096 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1966-67, 229095 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1968-69, 229094 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1969-70, 229093 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1970-71, 229092 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1971-72, 229091 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1972-73, 229090 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1974-75/76, 229089 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1976-77, 229088 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1980/81-84/85, 229087 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 1985/86-87/88, 229086 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - 1988/89-89/90, 229085 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1990/91-93/94, 229084 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1994/95-97, 229083 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1999/2000-, 229082 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Theater Programs, 2001-2004; 229081 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Series IV: O-Week Handbooks, 1970-1997, 229077
  - O- [orientation] week handbooks, 1970-94, 229079; As of 7/24/2019, O-week Books for '73,'84,'89, and '95 are missing. --GP (Box 15)
  - O- [orientation] week handbooks, 1995, 1997, 1998, 2001, 2003, 229078 (Box 16)
- Series V: Recordings, LPs, 229074
  - Will Rice College Chorus, 33 RPM, 229076 (Box 16)
    General note
    Side One: 1. Laetentur Coeli, Hassler (1:45); 2. Adoramus Te, Palestrina (1:53); 3. Agincourt Song, Dunstable (2:58); 4. Te Deum, A. Gabrieli (1:51); 5. Tenebrae Factae Sunt, Davyye (2:33); 6. Glory and Honor Are Before Him, J.S.Bach (2:51)
    Side Two: 1. The Battle of Jericho (1:15); 2. Cool Water (3:21); 3. Fratres In Unum (1:55); 4. Drinking Song (0:55); 5. Whiffenpoof Song (2:55)
  - Will Rice Winning Chorus 1967 - Recorded through the generosity of Sam and Helen Worden, 45 PRM, 229075 (Box 16)
    Side One: 1. Sicut Locutus Est, Bach; 2. Thou, Lord, Our Refuge, Mendelssohn
    Side Two: 1. Exaltabo Te, Johann Ernst Eberlin
  - Will Rice Winning Chorus 45 RPM, 1967 (Box 16)
- Series VI: T-shirts, 229062
  - Will Rice College Sweatshirt, n.d.; 229073 (Box 17, Item 1)
  - Beer Bike - Viva Will Rice, 1997; 229072 (Box 17, Item 2)
  - Beer Bike - Booze N the Hood, 1998; 229071 (Box 17, Item 3)
  - Beer Bike - Nitro, 1999; 229070 (Box 17, Item 4)
  - Beer Bike - Myth, Power, Value, 1999; 229069 (Box 17, Item 5)
  - O-Week - Mafios-O-Week, 1997; 229068 (Box 17, Item 6)
  - O-Week - Oh, Behave Week, 1999; 229067 (Box 17, Item 7)
  - O-Week - Play-doh Week, 2000; 229066 (Box 17, Item 8)
  - Band in the Quad, Fall 2004; 229065 (Box 17, Item 9)
  - Will Rice Theater (1 of 2), n.d.; 229064 (Box 17, Item 10)
  - Will Rice Theater (2 of 2), n.d.; 229063 (Box 17, Item 11)
- Series VII: Audio/Visual, 229054
  - Guys and Dolls Act I (8mm Camcorder Tape), March 1994; 229061 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Guys and Dolls Act II (8mm Camcorder Tape), March 1994; 229060 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Once Upon a Mattress (8mm Camcorder Tape), April 8, 1995; 229059 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Oklahoma Act I (8mm Camcorder Tape), November 1995; 229058 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Oklahoma Act II (8mm Camcorder Tape), November 1995; 229057 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Broadway Dessert (8mm Camcorder Tape), March 21, 1999; 229056 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Hair (8mm Camcorder Tape), November 2001; 229055 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Series VIII: Rice in a Box Memorabilia, 229045
  - Activities, 2012; 229053 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - O-[orientation] week handbooks, 2011; 229052 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photos, 229051 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Glassware, 2012; 229050 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Beer Koozie, 2012; 229049 (Box 19, Item 1)
  - Beer Bike - Beerthoven's Fifth (t-shirt), 2012; 229048 (Box 19, Item 2)
  - Karma Patrol (t-shirt), 229047 (Box 19, Item 3)
  - O-Week - Dojo Week, 2011; 229046 (Box 19, Item 4)
- Series IX: Scrapbook, 1970-1971, 229043
  - Will Rice Scrapbook, 1970-1971, 229044 (Box 20)
    Contains newsclippings, photographs, and other print ephemera
- Series X: Oversized Materials, 229040
  - Collage, 2010-2011; 229042 (Map-drawer 148, Item 11)
    General Note
    Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs, Part 3 of 3 (UA 226-3)
  - Photograph of James Street and Edythe Fulton, Masters of Will Rice College, 229041 (Map-drawer 148, Item 15)
- Series XI: Residential College Management Advisory Committee [RCMAC], 1980-1987; 229034
  - 1980/1981, 229039 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1981/1982, 229038 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1982/1983, 229037 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 1983/1984, 229036 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1986/1987, 229035 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Series XII: Governance, 1961-2013; 228981
  - Buddy System Proposal for Will Rice College, 2007; 229033 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1997/1998; 229032 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1998/1999; 229031 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Caregivers, 1998/1999; 229030 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "College Directions: What's Next?", 1967; 229029 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Constitution, 1984/1985; 229028 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Constitution, 1993; 229027 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Constitution, 1994; 229026 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Constitution, 1996; 229025 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Constitution, 1998; 229024 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Constitution - Revisions, 1980-2005; 229023 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Diet Directory, 1990/1991; 229022 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Diet Directory, 1991/1992; 229021 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Diet Directory, 1992/1993; 229020 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Diet Directory, 1993/1994; 229019 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Diet Directory, 1994/1995; 229018 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Diet Directory, 1995/1996; 229017 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Diet Directory, 1996/1997; 229016 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Diet Directory, 1997/1998; 229015 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Diet Directory, 1998/1999; 229014 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Diet Directory, 1999/2000; 229013 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Diet Directory, 2000/2001; 229012 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Directory, 1992/1993; 229011 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Directory, 1993/1994; 229010 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Directory, 1999/2000; 229009 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Directory, 2000/2001; 229008 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Directory, n.d.; 229007 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Elections, 1988-1999; 229006 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Fellows, 1961-2013; 229005 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - International Liaison Responsibilities, n.d.; 229004 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - President's Papers - Andy Tucker, 1989/1990; 229003 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - President's Papers - Edward B. Adams, 1990/1991; 229002 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - President's Papers - Doug Farry, 1991/1992; 229001 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - President's Papers - Stela Balderas, 1992/1993; 229000 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - President's Papers - Merritt McKinney, 1993/1994; 228999 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - President's Papers - Ian Marquadt, 1994/1995; 228998 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - President's Papers - J.P. Lopez, 1995/1996; 228997 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - President's Papers - Mitch Hollberg, 1996/1997; 228996 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - President's Papers - Jeremiah Helm/Michelle Glassman, 1997/1998; 228995 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - President's Papers - Curt Petersen, 1999/2000; 228994 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Rice Roommate Form, 2010; 228993 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Treasurer's Papers - Barry Donovan, 1988/1989, 1989/1990; 228992 (Box 22, Folder 42)